software engineering radio episode 66
and Gary macro on security
[Music]
hello listeners
welcome again to software engineering
radio this episode Misha L will
interview Gary McGraw on security but
before we get started let me again
remind you for a listener survey we have
got a couple of replies a couple of
people have filled in the survey forms
but we need more so please everybody go
to our website se - radio dotnet and
click the link to take the survey again
you can win a bunch of books Wiley and
daepung have provided us with a couple
of books books to give away and of
course German folks will get German
books we won't send German books to
english-speaking audience and well we
won't sell the data or do anything
commercially with it we just want to
know who you are to improve your
experience of SU radio to
optimize topics we are talking about and
so on so please do us a favor and go to
se - radio dotnet click on the survey
link and fill in the survey you're doing
us a great great favor thanks and now
let's get on with the episode today
Michelle and Gary McGraw Gary is
security expert and CTO of a security
company Gary why don't you introduce
yourself briefly well it's good to be
here Michael I'm Gary McGraw I'm the CTO
digital and i'm a software security
expert which is what we're going to be
talking about today
right so so how did you get started and
software security at all I got started
in
1996 which was about eleven years ago
now and what happened was I was very
much interested in programming languages
and in particular when Java came out I
thought that it was going to be
fantastic to have a
programming language for the web and
then of course I got it when it was in
alpha and it turned out to be more like
C++ with a few web bells and whistles
thrown in then it was like my favorite
programming language which is scheme but
I got very much interested in the claims
that Sun Microsystems and others were
making about Java because they were
saying things like any code that you
write in Java can be secure and I
thought what in the heck are these guys
talking about so I started getting very
deeply into Java security and I ended up
helping Edie Felton and the guys at
Princeton to break the Java Virtual
Machine many many times we got lots and
lots of press and and we learned a lot
of interesting lessons and then I wrote
a book called Java security with Edie so
after that it really made me wonder why
it was that these incredible language
designers and these incredible engineers
like Gosling and guy Steele and Bill joy
had screwed this up you know and if you
were a builder of systems and you wanted
not to screw things up from a security
perspective where would you turn to
learn how to do that in particular if
you were developer where would you turn
and you know what the answer was the
answer was there was nowhere to turn so
I decided to blaze a new trail and
start working on software security right
about that so I guess your best friend
was Sundin or how was the relationship
it turned out in the end to be just fine
in the beginning there was a woman there
named Marianne Muller who was a pretty
good security person but not really a
software person and when Java 1.2 came
out when JDK 1.2 which was also called
Java 2 came out they had replaced
Marianne with another guy who's now a
good friend of mine named Li Gong Li was
for a while a scientist at at Stanford
Research International Sr I and so I
knew him from the scientific community
and we got on great and so did Ed Felten
and all these other guys so now we work
together very closely and of course it
wasn't just Sun stuff that was broken we
we ended up poking holes in the virtual
machines of Netscape if you remember
Netscape from back then and also of
Microsoft when Microsoft finally
released Internet Explorer 3 which I
believe was in 1998 so you know is
interesting back then I think what
happened in the beginning was they
ignored us because they thought oh yeah
it's just a bunch of theory and then the
press got wind of it and it became quite
a big story and they were forced to face
up to the security challenges that they
had and they did a pretty good job a
dressing room I
wonder what kind of mentality what kind
of talent do you need to break the ends
to to be so interested and then breaking
other stuff yeah you know that's a good
question I thought I grew up that way um
you might have I don't know if you have
in Germany these little cars these toys
that you put in a slot and they run on
electricity you press a button and and
the cars drive themselves around do you
have those cars yeah we have them as
well yes so that was called a rural
racetrack in the States and I had one of
those cars and the first thing I did was
take the car apart figure out how it
worked and I figured out that it had an
electro magnetic motor in there and I
also sort of knew a little bit about how
those motors work so I took some copper
wire and put a few more little lines on
my motor so that it would be more
powerful and then my car would beat
everybody else's car because it had a
more powerful motor of course I never
told anybody about the extra-wide
but if you if you did the wrong thing
back then if you press the button all
the way down the car would fly off the
track because it was too powerful
[Laughter]
but you know I was born with that
mentality so it when it comes to
technology and it comes to especially
programming things because I've been
programming since I was 16
you know I actually 15 1981 I've always
wondered
how things really work and and what you
can do to learn about how they work and
and take them apart okay so I see so how
does it help you today as a security
expert how does it typical day look like
I'm not sure I'm not sure I have typical
days for a security guy because you know
because I wrote Java security and then I
followed it up with a book in 1999
called building secure software and then
I have one 2004 called exploiting
software and I had another one in 2006
called software security my books are
pretty popular so I've become kind of a
famous security guy and so I think my
life is not very typical
mostly what I find myself doing these
days is flying around planet Earth and
telling people what I wrote down in the
book and that they didn't want to read
they wanted me to tell them instead so
you met other people trying to break
others code then well we you know we do
a lot of deeply technical work when when
we're working on a book for example I
have a new book will chat about in a
while called exploiting online games and
it's about world of warcraft and these
massive multiplayer online role-playing
games MMORPGs which have literally
millions of subscribers okay's and and
we wrote a lot of code to break those
games and so in the book you'll see not
only ideas about how the games break but
actually code that you can type into
your own editor and compile yourself and
then you can run it against Warcraft and
it'll actually do interesting things
okay we get back to the book topic
pretty pretty soon let me cover some
some general security topics so it would
have to explain software security to a
person what where would you start which
topics are most relevant
what is already what is the problem and
what is already in solution when we talk
about authorization
authentication non-repudiation and
all in five minutes or less so so so
software security is about how to
approach computer security if you are a
developer or a software architect and so
the key to understanding security in my
opinion is having people who build our
systems
think carefully about security while
they're building them and there are a
number of best practices that I've
identified over the last decade working
on this that I believe all developers
and all software projects should take
advantage of there are seven touch
points I call them which are these best
practices I'll give you an example of
the top two touch points one is using a
static analysis tool which is very much
like works for the same way as a
compiler now you run it against your
code and in order to find security bugs
in your code and if you run a tool like
that it will find bugs like buffer
overflows and simple race conditions and
the kinds of small defects or bugs that
people write in their code all the time
because they just don't know any better
um C and C++ are particularly bad about
having many many ways to shoot yourself
in the foot from a security perspective
and so we need these tools to help us
identify places in the code where we've
made a mistake
another touch point an equally important
touch point is called architectural risk
analysis and the idea there is to look
for higher-level defects in your
software system that happened at the
design level it just so happens that if
you think about where defects are in
software from a security perspective it
turns out that there are two major
categories bugs in the implementation
and flaws in the design and it and they
they chunk up about 50/50 so if you did
a perfect job writing your
implementation in C++ say and you didn't
have any security bugs you could still
have some big security flaws for example
you might forget to authenticate the
user at all and that would be a design
issue and my practice and Microsoft's
experience and everybody who's been
working on this for the last decade we
all agree that that we have to solve
both the implementation problem and the
architecture problem and that's what my
book software security is all about so
my company's digital we have about a
hundred guys right now and we do most of
our work in North America but we help
very large corporations especially in
the financial vertical like Morgan
Stanley and fidelity and other very
large
organizations qualcomm to get a handle
on the software security problem by
teaching their developers and believe it
or not some of these banks have ten
thousand developers like morgan stanley
has ten thousand developers teaching
these guys about those best practices
and teaching them what security bugs
look like showing them security exploits
in living detail as we have in our book
exploiting software which is a hugely
popular book and and then changing the
institution so that the software
development lifecycle has these best
practices integrated into it and really
that's that software security in a
nutshell it's something that people
started practicing actively in right
about nineteen ninety eight and so you
know we've been doing it for about nine
years and i think a lot of developers
have come to realize that if we want to
tackle the security problem part of the
job is going to have to be done by them
okay i guess also reviewers are part of
that because i might have the feeling
that I designed it right and then secure
but I I need some other person's
feedback maybe our trial to exploit it
to be really sure how can I ever be sure
that there's no flaw no security a hole
in there anymore yeah so both
architectural risk analysis and code
review with a static analysis tool are
kinds of review and the answer is that
no you cannot be 100% certain that you
found all the security problems but if
you do consider
the code and you do consider the design
in light of security you're going to be
a lot better off than if you just sort
of really nearly ship code and don't
think about security and so though
there's no guarantee it's very clear
that when it comes to certain kinds of
software in particular financial
services software or software that
control say power plants or
telecommunications or
transportation devices that that that
that kind of software really needs to go
through the security wringer so we've
done that kind of review for she's
almost a decade now there's a funny
story though you know I've broken many
many many systems I can't even begin to
count the number over the years me and
my guys and about eighty percent of the
time when you go to the software team
and you say hey we found a security
problem in your system and let us show
it to you their reaction even if they
pay you to do it their reaction will be
well you're not supposed to do that
that's not allowed you know no user
would ever actually do that and we have
to very carefully explain to them that
we're the bad guy right then we're not
playing by the rules and that yes bad
guys do in fact do stuff like this and
that's part of part of software security
is getting people to understand how to
think like a bad guy and why I wrote
exploiting sucker in fact and also why I
wrote exploiting online games recently
what is one of the the biggest security
holes that you discovered in the past I
think the biggest one I was involved
with
Microsoft had tried to build a special
flag into their C compiler in order to
avoid buffer overflows and it was based
on Crispin cow and stack guard idea and
so the idea was that you would keep an
eye on the execution stack inside the
machine and if your little cookie got
stomped on by somebody's buffer overflow
it would throw an exception well the day
that that system was released Microsoft
had just been making a very big deal
about software security and you know
Bill Gates had rented out half of San
Francisco and they talked about the
trustworthy computing initiative and all
this stuff and they were getting lots of
press and this was one of the first
things that they released well the day
that it was released we broke it and we
showed how you could use the security
mechanism itself to carry out a security
attack so that became a huge story I was
on
seeing in and that story went worldwide
and I actually was traveling as 2002 I
was traveling to Finland and when I got
to Finland the Finnish press wanted to
talk about it so I did all these
interviews with Finnish newspapers and
it was in the International Herald
Tribune and that story went worldwide so
I'd say that was probably the biggest
one needless to say Microsoft wasn't too
pleased with
that result and you know to this day I
think they still are not very happy with
me but oh well you know they should just
build better software and then that
wouldn't happen you're not supposed to
be friend with everybody as a security
guy
well I'm glad you see it that way
Michael I agree with you completely
what is the first thing that you do when
you try to break a software well the
first thing you do is you think like a
bad guy or you think like somebody who
really wants to understand how the
system works and then determine what
kind of assumptions that the designer of
that system made so to go back to the
car example from before you know the
assumption that the people who made that
little car game had made was that nobody
would take the cars apart and
re-engineer the cars to be faster and
that that assumption turned out to be
not a very good one and so see bad guys
will take a look at a system and say oh
look they're assuming that the user will
always put in a name what if we put in a
script instead or look they're assuming
that you know input will only be
300k or whatever how about if we put in
a terabyte and see what happens and and
those are the sorts of things that you
always try first now you can do that in
a very principled way in exploiting
software we identified a whole bunch of
things that we called attack patterns
and the attack patterns are now 48 ways
to think about things that attackers
usually do when they see certain kinds
of software and I think if you
internalize some of those attack
patterns it helps you think like a bad
guy in a more interesting way one thing
that came to my mind is open saw
software might be more dangerous or
alluring more attacks because guys like
you they they can figure out from the
source code where the weak points are
and then try to attack exactly their
what what is your opinion there am i
right that turns out to be wrong but you
have many some very good reasons for
thinking it's right so let me explain
why it isn't it turns out that in order
to carry out an attack against a piece
of software having the source code is
certainly helpful but it is by no means
necessary and most people who do
software exploit actually use the binary
code
you know as the target and you wield
things like D compilers and
disassemblers and you look at the stack
as the machine is running and you know
you keep track of you use a lot of
debuggers and and low-level things and
so in my experience having the source
code is you know not really a necessary
thing so it turns out that open source
is in not really in any worse shape than
any other kind of software because of
the kind of tools that attackers use one
other thing to note their open source is
also no better off from a security
perspective because there's this theory
that you know there are many eyes
looking at it and so everybody will find
the bugs and the bugs are transparent
but I believe that that's just
completely you know baloney bull
feathers is what we call it over here
ok so let's get on to your latest book
exploiting online games so who is
concerned with that like only the gamers
or can you also derive some lessons
learned from for everybody using their
internet oh absolutely their lesson
Florent for everybody I learned a lesson
in my career of writing all these books
and the lesson that I learned was when
you write a book about how something
breaks everybody wants it and it's a
best-seller and when you write a book
about how to do software security
properly it doesn't sell near as well
so so if you want people to understand
the software security problem and you
want it to be widely understood the only
way to do that is to write about how
things break and I learned that lesson
you know more than once and I can tell
you that it's absolutely true I call it
the NASCAR effect you know what NASCAR
is the I know knows code but still
explain well people watch NASCAR which
is the kind of car racing so they can
see these guys crash their cars and
sometimes die and that's why humans are
interested in watching NASCAR doesn't
have anything to do with car
architecture or safety or you know
actual races it has mostly to do with
spectacular crashes and so I think that
computer security shares things by
analogy a lot sadly enough but by true
yeah yeah I can guess yeah yeah so so
the the
getting back to these online games these
games have become hugely popular like
there's one game called world of
warcraft you've probably heard of it has
8 million subscribers 8 million people
play that game on planet earth and
they're on in every country you know
they're two and a half million in China
a million and a half in the United
States lots and lots in Europe and the
subscriber base is very large the world
is available in many many languages and
as a result because all these people are
spending time playing a game and it's an
adventure game so you have characters
and they get levels and you can gain
experience points and you can find
pretend gold and you can buy virtual
swords of pain NASA T and you know
blunderbusses of flatulence and all
sorts of other items and it turns out
that these pretend items have real
economic value in the real world and
that there are companies set up to buy
those items from gamers and then sell
them to other gamers acting as a
middleman the biggest company on the
does that is called IgE because of this
you know there's incentive to gained
wealth in the game and have your
character you know go as far as possible
not just psychological incentive of
having a cool character but also real
monetary incentive of hey I can sell
this if I want so because of that as you
might imagine cheating is unbelievably
rampant all sorts of people cheat for
example you might want to have a program
called a bot play your character for you
while you sleep so you set up a bot so
that your character stands in front of a
monster hole and whenever a monster
comes out it kills it and you come in
the morning and there's a big pile of
gold and a bunch of dead monsters and
you know you were sleeping
so that's that's one of the one of the
examples from online games now let's get
technical for a minute here the way that
these games really work it's by having a
bank of central servers that are
connected over the Internet to fat
clients on PC so the gamers each have
their own PC and on that is a big
program that you know displays things
about the world and the character and
all that stuff it's kind of your view
into the universe well as you can
imagine the internet is not fast enough
it's not even fast enough for you and I
to talk over Skype without jitter right
exactly so it's not it's also not fast
enough to push all the possible state to
all of the gamers at once because you
know that there may be 8 million
subscribers but about 500,000 people are
playing this game at any one time so
right now when you're listening to this
podcast there are half a million people
playing World of Warcraft together and
you know the Internet's not fast enough
for all this stuff to happen in perfect
synchrony so the way the designers have
approached this problem is by taking a
piece of the state of the universe which
is stored on these servers and cracking
it off and handing that state over to
the clients program the game program on
the on the gamers PC now imagine that
you know how computers work and all of a
sudden you get all this state from the
game on your own PC and you want to
cheat well there's some obvious things
you can do like let's find out what kind
of state the game is providing me with
and here's a real example from world of
warcraft the game keeps track of your
characters location by allowing your
game client on your PC to attract those
XYZ coordinates and they're just stored
in memory somewhere so if you find out
where those are stored you can directly
change those coordinates not through
walking or running or flying but instead
by just programmatically poking new
values and then those new values will be
sent to the central server and your
character will teleport across the
universe
amazing it's awesome it's really it's
really incredible and as you can imagine
this ability to teleport throughout the
universe becomes extremely useful in
cheating and also in you know fighting
other players in player versus player
combat or other monsters haha and we
explained in the book you know how this
works and actually show code to do that
teleporting and ping pong and other
other techniques so that that's the now
here's why this is important one more
thing the these huge distributed systems
with you know hundreds of thousands of
users are exactly what we are setting
out to build in so ax and web 2.0 system
today and so my belief as a computer
scientist and you know a guy who does
research in computer security is the
kinds of problems around state in time
that are very common in these games like
World of Warcraft are exactly the kinds
of problems we're going to see for a
decade to come in all of this other
software that we're building for Sowa
and web 2o system
well so now that you tell me that there
are security holes the game companies of
course they they have already closed all
the security holes our how how fast do
they react are they aware of the Falls
they're certainly aware that people
cheat and their their approach so far
has been to try to determine when
somebody's cheating and kick their
character out of the game and they do
that by installing spyware in the case
of World of Warcraft on your PC to watch
what you're doing on your PC and not
just what the game application is doing
but all sorts of other aspects of what's
going on on your PC so they know who
you're connected to with your instant
messenger they know the names of all of
your windows that are open or all your
windows that have prophecies and they
know which dll's are loaded and they
send that information back to the server
to determine whether or not you're
cheating now that kind of activity in
California at least is certainly nowhere
near legal you can't install spyware on
someone's machine even if they said you
can you still can't but nobody's
challenged that from a legal perspective
in the United States yet but but you can
see that their approach so far has by
and large been one of monitoring and
trying to determine that people are
cheating and it's so kicking them off
the system but it's a it's a classic
Tsar arm 3 I think many of the attacks
and much of the codes that we use in the
book are already known and so you you
probably shouldn't use that code to
cheat because if you do you'll get your
character banned off the game what can i
as an individual do or do about it just
yeah either a more does your book give
me any advice on this yeah it actually
does in the last chapter we have a
gamers security checklist that has 15
things on it that gamers should think
about and ask about their game and so in
the book if you're a gamer you can use
that checklist to think about your own
situation and determine what to do
there's also a lot of advice in the book
for people who are designing and
building these games and in fact we
spent a fair amount of time talking to
game developers about how to do better
job when you're designing a game and so
many of the things that we've pointed
out could in fact be fixed in future
games which I believe is important you
know because if you have games like
Second Life which I'm sure you've heard
of yeah that would have been the next
question yeah what's about second life
second life you know in in these games
second life the guys Linden Labs have
decided that all of the virtual stuff
that you build for your avatar belongs
to you now that's a lot different than
most game companies because you know the
game companies like world of warcraft
guys the blizzard guys actually just
licensed you
you know your character and all your
character stuff really still belongs to
Blizzard
but in Second Life it belongs to you now
here's a funny legal situation get this
this is a real case going on right now
in the u.s. court system there was a guy
in Pennsylvania who by watching how
Second Life worked determined a way to
use URL parameter tampering to bid for
and win auctions on land that hadn't
even been opened up yet and he became a
real estate Baron in Second Life by
doing this and then he started you know
selling the land and renting it and
doing all the other stuff because it was
his land well the Linden Labs guys found
out that he had used parameter tampering
and so they took all of his land away
and they kicked him out of the game and
he said wait a minute that's not your
land that's my land according to this
legal situation so I'm going to sue you
and so right now there's a lawsuit in
court about this guy who used a bug in
the code to gain property that he claims
as his that they took away without any
reason and that's just very interesting
how it's going to come out who knows you
know imagine you're the judge who's used
to you know real world stuff where
somebody's cow destroyed somebody's
fence you know and that's what he
usually sees and all of a sudden there's
some guy who's mad because his pretend
stuff was taken away by a game company
the songs are so far off but I guess
there is more to come in the future
absolutely I think credibly fascinating
I had so much fun working on this book
for the last year and a half because
every time I would think through an
issue it would have all these incredible
facets and it was just a complete blast
to work on this thing so I'm
really grateful to my co-author Gregg
Hoglund that he conned me into doing it
because it's working on this work it's
just been really really fun
so what kind of advice do you have for
the second live people I mean you found
us we just heard about this one exploit
but what are other potential exploits
are around for I mean the biggest piece
of advice is you should understand that
you're gamers your users are going to
cheat and you should disincentivize them
from doing so so you should you should
try to think in advance of how people
are going to break your system and make
it so that it's much harder to break
then it might be otherwise and that's
you know the number one piece of advice
going back to what we were talking about
in generic software security do things
like code reviews but more importantly
think very hard about time and state and
do some architectural risk analysis to
determine the kinds of attacks that
attackers are very likely to carry out
on your game system and that's why I
think you know exploiting online games
for all of its coolest factor and you
know for all of its great stories
actually has very important lessons for
technologists think about from a
software security perspective which is
another reason that I wrote the book is
could you give me some more examples of
the concrete technical advices that did
you get you mean for people that are
building separation or building some
people who are building software game
software yeah well here's a piece of
technical advice that you can glean by
only by reading the whole book and that
is you know any piece of state that you
give to the gamer is very likely to be
manipulated and so you need to figure
out an efficient way to compare the
previous state from last time you got
something from the gamer's pc2 the
current thing that they're asking for
and maybe you could use something as
simple as you know momentum or inertia
against a huge pile of data and use some
heuristics and techniques from AI to
determine whether or not you know big
orthogonal jumps in state space have
occurred versus sort of smooth
you know what you would expect kind of
changes in state that would be very very
very helpful but I'm not aware of any
game that's doing that sort of thing
right now okay so you have something
like the suggested idealistic
architecture for them I mean where to
keep State and thing like that that that
is part of an architecture decision
right that's right it's part of an
architecture decision and so what you
have to say as well as we design these
future games we need to think very
carefully about the kind of architecture
that we adopt and and I think the same
lessons apply to like I said before so a
software and web 2o software where
people are making these architecture
decisions for example you know the
Google Desktop Search
that's suffered from a number of
spectacular problems that look very
similar to the time and state errors
that we described in the online games
and so sure enough you know here we go
the next set of problems that we
experienced in the software security
world are going to be more about time
and State and things like race
conditions and lockout and desire
situations because there's so much state
to track then they are going to be about
dumb things like cross-site scripting
and buffer overflows and and the
software security problems of yesterday
so what is the next book this book is on
what is the next book that you wrote
you already making me do the next book I
haven't even had fun with this one yet
it just got released last week I'm
actually working on a book that's going
to take a long time to write about
security principles like the principle
of least privilege or the principle of
careful error handling and I'm trying to
demonstrate those principles which are
abstract philosophical things
using real code so that people who are
you know real honest-to-god hardcore
coders can begin to understand some of
the architectural issues that they need
to think about while they're designing
their program and you know it's
interesting to take a while yet that
would done but it'll be cool when it's
done yeah no I I've been involved in the
patterns community quite heavily so I I
wondered whether how close this gets to
two patterns actually principles are
alike behind patterns they up the basic
foundation and then the concrete design
solutions that that typically work that
that showed that they work that proof
that they didn't become patterns will
will you Express patterns in there or
stay at a principles level I want to I
want to go from principles to code and
we may go through patterns if we need to
but I do want to say one thing a lot of
people that first think about software
security did it that are good
programmers and designers often think
that software security must be about
features and functions and things and
stuff like if I just add cryptography
then I'll take care of all the security
issues well what I've been explaining
over the last while that we've been
talking is that security is much more
than features and functions and stuff
and things security is really much more
like quality it's much more about
building something that's solid that
will stand up under attack and making
sure it's this defect free as possible
and so that's a critical critical lesson
so I want to show people in this book
not just a set of patterns that you can
use to do the right sort of functions
like if you're thinking about how to do
authentication right yes but also how to
avoid common mistakes that people make
in designs when they're maybe doing
authentication just as an example yeah
sons sons exciting when can I have it
you said
you really are a taskmaster Michael I'm
not making no promises you know what
that that work is just barely underway
and you know I need some time to rest
and have a fun time with exploiting
online games because that one's so new
and it's so exciting yeah I just wanted
to tease you so
great so any final words you want to say
any message to our listeners well my
final word is that I'm hugely optimistic
about software security there are a lot
of people who express a lot of pessimism
about security and they say oh woe is us
we're never gonna solve these problems
we should all just despair and stick our
heads in the sand and maybe even you
know flip burgers for a living instead
of a Down software but I'm not like that
I think that we over the last 10 years
since I've been working on software
security have made huge amounts of
forward progress and that I think the
time has come that most people who are
building systems understand that they
need to worry about security they're
just not quite sure what to do yet and
so the time of teaching people how to do
the right stuff from a security
perspective is now and I'm very excited
to be helping to lead the charge and
teaching people how to do this stuff so
I'd say you know a final word is I'm
optimistic about the progress we've made
and I want everybody to help so come
help great thanks Kerry you're
absolutely welcome that was really fun
Michael
[Music]
thanks for listening to software
engineering radio if you want to get
more information about software
engineering radio or if you want to give
us feedback please go to our website at
se - radio dot net you can also contact
the team at team at SAE - radio net
although we prefer entries in our
comment system on the website so other
people can see what you think software
engineering radio wants to thank Henning
Poli for the intro and outro music as
well as Lipson for providing the
bandwidth this episode of se radio as
well as all other episodes is licensed
under Creative Commons license see the
software engineering radio website for
details